<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://gabrielc1925.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://gabrielc1925.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-08-15T20:32:50+00:00</updated><id>https://gabrielc1925.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Gabriel J. Chavez</title><subtitle>The CV for Gabriel Chavez. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Protect your identity</title><link href="https://gabrielc1925.github.io/blog/2024/Protect-your-identity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Protect your identity"/><published>2024-08-14T07:45:30+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-14T07:45:30+00:00</updated><id>https://gabrielc1925.github.io/blog/2024/Protect-your-identity</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gabrielc1925.github.io/blog/2024/Protect-your-identity/"><![CDATA[<p>Living in the last few dacades have seen us become largely desensitized to the large number of data breaches that have been occuring and the massive risk of our identity getting stolen. There was a recent data breach that has the largest threat potential ever however, and we all need to change the way we handle our identity to prevent future problems.</p> <p>In the post titled <a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/story/2024-08-13/hacker-claims-theft-of-every-american-social-security-number#:~:text=According%20to%20a%20class%2Daction,staffing%20agencies%20and%20others%20doing">Hackers may have stolen the Social Security numbers of every American. How to protect yourself</a>, the details of the latest data breach are explained. Basically, a data broker was hacked and all of our most sensitive information has been leaked and is now for sale to bad actors. This includes Social Security numbers, full name, date of birth, address, and phone number for the affected individuals. There is no information on who is affected yet, but this is the opportunity we have to get ahead of the mess and protect ourselves from major losses from this and other data breaches.</p> <p>This is not a very difficult thing to do, but it is time consuming and can be risky if done incorrectly. You will be putting your sensitive data into forms to freeze your credit and other accounts. This sensitive data is being sent over the internet, so be sure to connect from your home wifi. <strong><em>Do not do this on a public wifi or unsecure network, as there is the potential (however low) that someone could intercept the data if they are connected to the same network.</em></strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal"/><category term="personal,"/><category term="identity"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to protect your identity from bad actors]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Website formatting complete</title><link href="https://gabrielc1925.github.io/blog/2024/website-formating-complete/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Website formatting complete"/><published>2024-04-28T07:45:30+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-28T07:45:30+00:00</updated><id>https://gabrielc1925.github.io/blog/2024/website-formating-complete</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://gabrielc1925.github.io/blog/2024/website-formating-complete/"><![CDATA[<p>I have completed the initial task of getting the website set up. This has overall been a very easy task thanks to all the work done by the team who developed this site layout. Many thanks to the <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio">Al-Folio</a> team for making this a very intuitive and pain free process.</p> <p>I especially appreciate that there are wonderful example files for all the different types of content that I might want to write. The auto-checking Github Actions and the thorough README file and accompanying documentation made this whole process pain free. There are a couple formatting issues on my CV related to dates that I need to figure out, but other than that everything worked perfectly out of the box.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="next-steps">Next Steps</h2> <p>My next task is going to be continuing to work on the collaborative project I have going with a few friends, the goal of which is to build a website template for easy deployment by a mosque. I will be learning more coding and development-centric skills to enable that, and may post separate projects for each language as I learn more.</p> <p>For now, you can follow along with my projects using the menu at the top of the page. Info on my main project can be found in the <a href="/projects/Masjid_Website">Masjid_Website </a> project page.</p> <p>Follow along with me as I learn and pave a path forward!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="website-status"/><category term="website,"/><category term="status-update"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Website formatting complete. Ready to start building.]]></summary></entry></feed>